BENSON NDIWA

Nairobi, Kenya +254 707 357 072 bnkimtai@gmail.com

A solution-driven full stack web developer adept at contributing to a highly collaborative work environment and finding solutions. I have proven experience developing consumer-focused web applications. I also possess good knowledge of the best practices for web design, user experience, security and speed.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance — *Software Developer*

June 2022 - Present

Completed multiple projects for clients on time and within budget, leading to increased repeat business and positive references.

Darna Limited, Nairobi — Intern Software Developer

June 2021 - May 2022

Developed and implemented new features that improved system performance by 30%, reducing processing time and increasing efficiency.

The National Treasury, Nairobi — *IT Support Attache*

April 2019 - August 2019

Resolved complex technical issues and provided expert support, reducing downtime and increasing productivity for employees and partners.

EDUCATION

Multimedia University of Kenya, Nairobi — Degree

September 2017 - December 2022

Bsc Information Technology

CERTIFICATION

Azubi Africa, Nairobi - AWS Re/Start Program

May 2022 - August 2022

AWS Cloud Practitioner

SKILLS

Full Stack Web Development
Desktop Applications
Bash Scripting
Docker, Linux
AWS Cloud Computing

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Javascript
Typescript
Angular
ReactJs
NodeJS

Java, Spring Boot Python

C#

MongoDB, SQL

PHP

LANGUAGES

English, Swahili

Github

https://github.com/Benson306

PORTFOLIO

https://benndiwa.netlify.com

PROJECTS

Ecommerce Web Application

An ecommerce web application with Cart, User dashboard and working payment options available. It also has an admin panel for management of orders, deliveries, products and delivery locations. Developed with React, Node.js, Express, MongoDb and Tailwind CSS

Real Estate Management System

A web application that enables real estate professionals to track residents, leases, maintenance tasks, collect rent, and handle finances to update operations and reduce costs. Developed with PHP, MySQL, CSS and uses the Safaricom Daraja API for mobile payment.

Utulivu Shopping Cart

A web application that allows a customer to browse, grab a product off the shelf, and head to the checkout counter to make a purchase. It has capability for enabling instant mobile payment. Developed with React, Redux, Node.js, MongoDb and Tailwind CSS.

Hospital ERP

A web application that aims at bringing quality in patient care & management with various important utilities like easy & quick patient registration, instant access to patient's complete health history, integrated patient module with various other related departments and many more. Developed with PHP, Javascript, MySQL and uses Mpdf to generate pdf receipts and records.

Brindex Course Search

A course finder application to compare diploma, undergraduate and postgraduate courses from colleges, top universities and higher education institutions across Kenya, including entry requirements. Developed with PHP, Javascript and MySQL

LINKEDIN

https://www.linkedin.com/in/benson-kimtai-ndiwa